Werner Seligmann Papers
Werner Seligmann Papers
- Project records
  - NORDWESTSTADT, COMPETITION Frankfurt, Germany (undated) (not built) [Residential], housing competition
    - Project material, undated; site plan, elevations, sections (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Slides, sections, plan; 1 (Box S-3)
  - NORTH BARRY STREET COMMUNITY BUILDING 112 N. Barry St., Olean, New York (1980) [Recreational]
    (Alternate names: Ash Community Center, Olean Senior Citizens Center)
    Extensive remodeling of senior citizens' center. Sponsor/client: City of Olean.
    - Drawings, 1977-1978; preliminary presentation and working drawings (Tube 97)
    - Project material, undated; elevations, plans, exterior (Box 51)
    - Slides, title slide (dated 1980), elevations, plans, construction and reconstruction, earlier existing structures, general, side and interior views; 95 (Box S-3)
  - NUSSBAUM MUSEUM, See FELIX NUSSBAUM HOUSE COMPETITION Osnabrueck, Germany.
  - OLD PORT HARBOR Ithaca, New York (not built) [Mixed Use], proposal for commercial building with apartments above
    - Drawings, 1971; plans, sections, perspectives (Tube 98)
    - Project material, undated; aerial perspective, plan, sections (Box 48)
    - Slides, site plan; 1 (Box S-3)
  - OLEAN CENTRAL FIRE STATION (OFS) 538 North Union St. Olean, New York (1980) [Government]
    New central fire station. Sponsor/client: City of Olean. Collaborators/partners: Engineering: Galson & Galson Consulting Engineers, Inc. (East Syracuse); Structural: Snyder, Burns, & Associates (Syracuse); Contractor: Smith Bros.: Photographer: Jon Reis (Ithaca).
    - Drawings, 1977; sketches and measured drawings (Tube 99)
    - Drawings, undated; early schemes, studies and presentation drawings (includes drawings for publication) (Tube 100)
    - Drawings, undated; working drawings, detail sheets, studies (Tube 101)
    - Drawings, 1977; working, structural and mechanical drawings (Tube 102)
    - Project material, 1980-1985; exterior and interior; sketch; award submission; revised bid form; article (Box 52)
    - Slides, drawings and sketches, elevations, sections, plans, construction, earlier existing structures, general and interior views; 160 (Box S-3)
    - Slides (cont.) (Box S-4)
  - OLEAN ELDERLY RESIDENTIAL PROJECT Olean, New York (not built) [Mixed Use]
    Elderly housing, senior citizens center, and commercial space. Sponsor/client: NYS Urban Development Corporation. Collaborators/partners: Project Architect: Robert Gitlin; Structural: Dr. Donald P. Greenberg; Mechanical and Electrical: Flack & Kurtz (NYC); Structural: Severud Associates (NYC); Construction: Scrufari Construction Company
    - Drawings, 1973; schematic design drawings, preliminary working drawings (Tube 103)
    - Drawings, undated; design development, preliminary working, and presentation drawings (Tube 104)
    - Drawings, 1973; working drawings (Tube 105)
    - Drawings, 1974-1976; structural and mechanical drawings (Tube 106)
    - Drawings, undated; presentation and publication drawings (Tube 107)
    - Project material, undated; site plans, elevations, sections, plans; program; award submission (Box 53)
    - Slides, title slide (dated 1974), site plans, elevations, sections, plans, models, axonometric; 25 (Box S-4)
  - OLEAN SENIOR CITIZENS CENTER, See NORTH BARRY STREET COMMUNITY BUILDING Olean, New York.
  - OPERA DE LA BASTILLE, COMPETITION Paris France (1983) (not built) [Cultural]
    Major international competition. Sponsor/client: Ministry of Culture, France.
    - Drawings, undated; sketches and trace drawings (Tube 108)
    - Drawings, undated; site maps, presentation drawings (Tube 109)
    - Presentation board 1, section, plan, axonometric
    - Project material, 1982-1984; sections, plans; competition materials; project description (Box 2)
    - Project material, oversize (Box 94C)
    - Slides, site plans, elevations, sections, isometrics; 30 (Box S-4)
  - PFORTZHEIM, COMPETITION* Pfortzheim, Germany (undated) (not built) [Residential]
    - Slides, models; 4 (Box S-4)
  - POTTER PAINT COMPANY OFFICE ADDITION, Cortland, New York (not built) [Commercial], small office addition
    - Project material, undated; plan (Box 95, Folder 32)
    - Project material, oversize (Box 94A)
    - Slides, plans, models; 2 (Box S-4)
  - PRINZ-ALBRECHT-PALAIS, COMPETITION Berlin, Germany (1984) (not built) [Cultural]
    Major international competition. Sponsor/client: City of Berlin.
    - Drawings, undated; base maps and drawings (Tube 110)
    - Drawings, 1983; sketches (Tube 111)
    - Drawings, undated; presentation drawings (Tube 112)
    - Drawings, undated; plan (Tube 113)
    - Presentation board 2, perspective
    - Presentation board 3, "Schnitt durch Vortragsraum, "Schnitt durch Ausstellung," Schnitt durch Ramps."
    - Presentation board 4, site plan (airbrushed)
    - Presentation board 5, perspective
    - Presentation board 6, map
    - Presentation board 7, map
    - Project material, 1983-1990; plan, elevations, sections, model; competition materials (in German); correpondence with courier company (Box 3)
    - Slides, title slide (dated 1984), map, analytic and explanatory diagrams, site plans, axonometrics, elevations, drawings and sketches, perspectives, sections, plans, models, earlier existing structures, referential images, art work; 150 (Box S-4)
  - REHABILITATION OF PRESIDENT'S RESIDENCE (SUNY CORTLAND) Cortland, New York (not built) [Residential]
    Kitchen and entry remodeling. Sponsor/client: NYS University Construction Fund.
    - Drawings, 1966; working drawings (Tube 114)
    - Project material, undated; elevation (Box 95, Folder 33)
  - RIPLEY MOTORS (RIP) Ithaca, New York (not built) [Commercial]
    Automobile showroom and service center. Sponsor/client: Ripley Motors
    - Drawings, 1963-1966; studies, working drawings (Tube 115)
    - Project material, undated; elevation (Box 95, Folder 49)
    - Slides, elevation; 1 (Box S-4)
  - ROH HOUSING Ithaca[?], New York (not built) [Residential], small housing project
    - Drawings, 1964; sketches (Tube 116)
    - Slides, plans, sections; 7 (Box S-4)
  - ROOSEVELT ISLAND, COMPETITION, New York, New York (undated) (not built) [Residential]
    Low and middle income housing competition. Not submitted. Sponsor/client: NYS Urban Development Corporation
    - Drawings, undated; sketches and plans (Tube 117)
  - ROSEFSKY OFFICE*, Binghamton, New York (not built) [Commercial]
    Proposed modest remodeling of existing physician's office. Sponsor/client: Dr. Rosefsky.
    - Project material, oversize (Box 94A)
  - ROSEFSKY SUMMER HOUSE 1 Silver Lake, Pennsylvania (not built) [Residential]
    Summer residence including guest quarters and studio. Sponsor/client: Dr. and Mrs. Rosefsky
    - Drawings, 1967-1968; sketches and hardline studies (Tube 118)
    - Slides, sketches, elevations, models, general, back and side views; 35 (Box S-4)
  - ROSEFSKY SUMMER HOUSE 2A AND B Silver Lake, Pennsylvania (not built) [Residential]
    - Drawings, 1967-1968; sketches and hardline studies (Tube 118)
  - ROSEFSKY SUMMER HOUSE 3A, B, C Silver Lake, Pennsylvania (not built) [Residential]
    - Project material, 1973; elevation, section, perspective (Box 67)
    - Drawings, 1968-1974; sketches, hardline studies and preliminary drawings (Tube 119)
  - ROSEFSKY SUMMER HOUSE 4A, B Silver Lake Pennsylvania (not built) [Residential]
    - Drawings, 1968-1974; sketches, hardline studies and preliminary drawings (Tube 119)
    - Drawings, student re-drawings (Tube 176)
    - Model, poor condition; approximate dimensions: 32"L x16"W x2.5"H (Box Model-6)
  - ROSEFSKY SUMMER HOUSE 5 Oquaga Lake, New York (not built) [Residential]
    - Drawings, 1974; sketches and preliminary working drawings (Tube 120)
    - Drawings, miscellaneous (Tube 176)
  - SAGAN RESIDENCE* Ithaca, New York (not built) [Residential]
    Residence for astronomer Carl Sagan and wife, Linda. Sponsor/client: Carl and Linda Sagan.
    - Drawings, 1972; work location maps, preliminary working drawings (Tube 121)
    - Slides, models; 30 (Box S-4)
  - SANGSAR HOUSING Sangsar Iran (not built) [Residential]
    Workers and administrators housing. Sponsor/client: Hajabar Yazdani (owner); Technical Consultant Services Associates - H. Sharifi/Henry Javaheri (Developers). Collaborators/partners: Architects: Finne/Perry Dean Partners/Kiley/Seligmann
    - Drawings, undated; presentation drawings (Tube 122)
    - Project material, undated; site plans, perspectives, sections, plans, model (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - Slides, site plans, plans, models; 20 (Box S-4)
  - SCHERZ RESIDENCE Homer, New York (not built) [Residential]
    New residence project. Sponsor/client: Herbert Scherz
    - Drawings, 1976; sketches (Tube 123)
    - Drawings, 1975; preliminary schemes, design development drawings, site studies (Tube 124)
    - Slides, models; 5 (Box S-4)
  - SCIENCE BUILDING II (SUNY CORTLAND) SEE ALSO BOX 93 (SCB II) SUNY Cortland Campus, Cortland, New York (1967) [Educational]
    Major addition with physics, chemistry and biology facilities. Sponsor/client: NYS University Construction Fund. Collaborators/partners: Engineers: Sargeant, Webster, Crenshaw & Folley (Syracuse); Contractor: Edward L. Nezelek, Inc. (Johnson City, NY); Photographer: ISAF Studio, C. Hadley Smith (Ithaca).
    See also Writings and biographical material: Scrapbook I; Writings and biographical material: Scrapbook III; Writings and biographical material: Miscellaneous.
    - Drawings, undated; base map, design development drawings (Tube 125)
    - Drawings, 1964-1965; design development drawings, working drawings (Tube 126)
    - Drawings, 1964; design development drawings (Tube 127)
    - Drawings, 1964-1965; preliminary working drawings, studies, perspectives (Tube 128)
    - Drawings, 1964; lab layouts (Tube 129)
    - Drawings, 1965; working drawings (Tube 130)
    - Drawings, 1966; heating, venting and circulation and electrical drawings (Tube 131)
    - Drawings, 1965; working drawings (Tube 132)
    - Drawings, 1965; working drawings (Tube 133)
    - Drawings, 1965; working drawings (Tube 134)
    - Drawings, 1965; "as-builts" (blueprints) (Tube 135)
    - Drawings, 1965; "as-builts" (blueprints) (Tube 136)
    - Drawings, undated; design and presentation drawings (Tube 137)
    - Drawings, 1964-1965; design and presentation drawings (Tube 138)
    - Presentation board 27, axonometric, first floor plan
    - Presentation board 28, section
    - Presentation board 29, section
    - Presentation board 30, south elevation
    - Presentation board 31, photo of exterior details
    - Presentation board 32, photo of lab
    - Presentation board 33, Elevation
    - Presentation board 34, Elevation
    - Presentation board 35, North elevation
    - Project material, 1964-1966; site plans, plan, elevations, sections, regulation lines, axonometrics, model; award submission; clipping; design report; text from exhibition board (Box 34)
    - Project material, 1966-1968; construction and completed interior details (Box 35)
    - Project material, undated; completed building (exterior) (Box 36)
    - Project material, undated; site plans, elevations, sections, axonometrics, plans, working details, regulation lines, perspectives (Box 37)
    - Project material, oversize (Box 94B)
    - Project material, oversize, undated; photos of building exterior (Tube 139)
    - Slides, analytical and explanatory diagrams, site plan, axonometrics, elevations, perspective, sections, construction, plans, models, facade, general views, lab details, interior details; 125 (Box S-4)
  - SELIGMANN OFFICE AND RESIDENCE REMODELING* 11 Homer Ave., Cortland, New York (1986) [Mixed Use]
    (Alternate names: Homer Ave. Nos. 9-11)
    Offices of Werner Seligmann and Associates. Continuous redesign and remodeling. Sponsor/client: Werner Seligmann.
    - Drawings, 1986; sketches, studies, working drawings (Tube 140)
    - Project material, undated; sketches of proposed gates (Box 95, Folder 71)
    - Slides, title slide (dated 1966), general and interior views; 95 (Box S-4)
  - SELIGMANN THESIS PROJECT (CORNELL UNIVERSITY) Ithaca, New York (1955) (not built) [Other]
    Seligmann's final thesis project for his undergraduate degree in architecture from Cornell University, consisting of a hotel for Cortland, New York.
    - Project material, 1955; plans, axonometric, perspective, model, and text (Box 95, Folder 75)
  - SIMON SHOP REMODELING, Cortland, New York (not built) [Commercial], small façade in interior remodeling
    - Drawings, 1964; preliminary working drawings (Tube 141)
  - SPROULL SUMMER RESIDENCE Cayuga Lake, New York (1968) [Residential]
    Summer house on shores of Cayuga Lake. Sponsor/client: Robert Sproull.
    - Drawings, 1983; sketches (Box 95, Folder 73)
    - Drawings, 1967-1968; sketches, studies, presentation and working drawings (Tube 142)
    - Drawings, student re-drawings (Tube 176)
  - STIGUM HOUSE Cortland[?], New York (not built) [Residential], small suburban house
    - Drawings, 1963; sketches (Box 95, Folder 69)
    - Slides, elevations, plans; 4 (Box S-4)
  - STUDENT PROJECTS* Ithaca, New York (not built) [Other]
    Presumably these were projects done while Seligmann was a student at Cornell University.
    - Project material, undated; photos of models, text (Box 95, Folder 83)
  - SYRACUSE UNIVERSITY CAMPUS CHARETTE* Syracuse, New York (not built) [Educational]
    A Seligmann-initiated project to involve faculty and students in developing more comprehensive plans for the development of the Syracuse University campus. Sponsor/client: Werner Seligmann.
    - Drawings, undated; presentation drawings (Tube 143)
    - Slides, section/elevation; 1 (Box S-4)
  - SYRACUSE UNIVERSITY RESIDENTIAL DORM COLLEGE* Syracuse, New York (not built) [Residential]
    A Seligmann-initiated proposal for the development of dormitories and a residential college at Syracuse University. Sponsor/client: Werner Seligmann.
    - Drawings, 1987; proposal drawings (Tube 144)
    - Project material, undated; site plans, sections, elevations, referential projects (Box 58)
    - Slides, site plan, elevations, perspective, section, plans, earlier existing structures, referential; 95 (Box S-4)
  - TEMPLE BRITH SHOLOM (TBS) 117 Madison St., Cortland, New York (1969) [Religious]
    Small suburban reformed synagogue and Seligmann's own synagogue. Sponsor/client: Temple Brith Sholom Congregation. Collaborators/partners: Structural; Dr. Donald P. Greenberg; Mechanical: Galson and Galson Consulting Engineers, Inc. (East Syracuse).
    - Drawings, 1968-1969; presentation and working drawings (Tube 145)
    - Drawings, 1968; sketches and working details (Tube 146)
    - Drawings, 1968; working drawings (blueprints) (Tube 147)
    - Model, restored; approximate dimensions: 16.5"L x12"W x8"H (Box Model-7)
    - Project material, 1969; site plans, plans, elevations, sections, model, exterior and interior; correspondence; dedication booklet; project (Box 38)
    - Slides, title slide (dated 1970), site plan, elevation, plans, models, general and interior views, exterior details; 170 (Box S-4)
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, Binghamton, New York, See JEFFERSON SCHOOL RENOVATION AND LIBRARY MEDIA CENTER 151 Helen St., Binghamton, New York.
  - TOKYO INTERNATIONAL FORUM, COMPETITION Tokyo Japan (1989) (not built) [Cultural]
    This was a major international competition for a large civic and cultural center. Sponsor/client: Tokyo Metropolitan Government (Bureau of Citizens and Cultural Affairs).
    - Drawings, undated; plans, sections, hardline studies, presentation drawings (Tube 148)
    - Drawings, undated; sketches and drawings on trace (Tube 149)
    - Drawings, student re-drawings (Tube 176)
    - Presentation board 12, Floor plans (offices, studio, exhibition halls, mezzanine, conference rooms), "F5813."
    - Presentation board 13, sections, plan, "F5813."
    - Presentation board 14, plans (bus/taxi stands, roof, truck docks), "F5813."
    - Presentation board 15, Elevations, section, "F5813."
    - Presentation board 16, site plan, roof plan, "F5813."
    - Project material, 1989; axonometrics, model, background images; sketches; list of student contributors; design conditions; competition materials (Box 8)
    - Project material, oversize (Box 94C)
    - Slides, elevations, perspectives, sections, plans, models, earlier existing structures, analytical and explanatory diagrams, competition entries by other architects; 95 (Box S-4)
  - TOPOGRAPHY OF TERROR, COMPETITION Berlin Germany (1993) (not built) [Cultural]
    This was an invited competition for a meeting hall and housing. Sponsor/client: City of Berlin.
    - Drawings, undated; base maps and presentation drawings (Tube 150)
    - Drawings, 1992-1993; sketches and drawings (Tube 151)
    - Drawings, undated; presentation drawings (Tube 152)
    - Drawings, 1992-1993; sketches and drawings (Tube 153)
    - Drawings, student re-drawings (Tube 176)
    - Project material, 1992-1993; elevations, plans, section, model; correspondence; competition materials (in German), notes (Box 4)
    - Slides, maps and city plans, analytical and explanatory drawings, site plans, elevations, sections, plans, models, earlier existing structures; 185 (Box S-4)
    - Slides (cont.) (Box S-5)
  - TRANSPORTABILITY UNIT* (not built) [Other]
    Prefabricated units for temporary housing.
    - Project material, undated; Elevations, plans, working details; text [Newspaper box] (Box 70)
    - Slides, plans, elevations, sections; 2 (Box S-5)
  - UTICA ELDERLY HOUSING, COMPETITION Utica, New York (1973) (not built) [Residential]
    This was an open competition for housing for the elderly. Sponsor/client: New York State Association of Architects Development Corporation and the City of Utica. Collaborators/partners: Photographer: C. Hadley Smith.
    - Drawings, undated; presentation drawings (Tube 154)
    - Project material, 1973; site plan, elevations, sections, plans; competition report (Box 59)
    - Slides, elevations, plans, models; 4 (Box S-5)
  - UTICA URBAN DESIGN STUDY (UT CDB) Utica, New York (not built) [Government]
    Urban design study of circulation, parking, and development possibilities. Sponsor/client: City of Utica.
    - Drawings, undated; preliminary working drawings (Tube 155)
    - Project material, 1970; site plan, elevations, sections, plans, model; study (Box 60)
    - Slides, maps, site plans, sections, plans; 55 (Box S-5)
  - VALLEY DEVELOPMENT FOUNDATION, Binghamton, New York (not built) [Government]
    The Valley Development Foundation (VDF) was a nonprofit organization founded by corporations in the Binghamton area seeking to spur development and undertake design initiatives and proposals. Projects sponsored by or otherwise related to the VDF include Binghamton City Hall Restoration, Binghamton Court Street Area Study, Capri Theater Impact Study, and Binghamton Urban Renewal Authority (BURA) - General.
  - WASHINGTON STREET, Binghamton, New York (undated) [Government]
    Redesign of major entry to city, including street alignment and paving, planting, lighting, signage and street furniture. Sponsor/client: Binghamton Urban Renewal Authority (BURA).
    - Project material, undated; site plan, section, working details (Box 25)
    - Slides, sections, plans, street furniture designs; 25 (Box S-5)
  - WEST VILLAGE, See ITHACA SCATTERED SITE HOUSING - ELM ST. Ithaca, New York.
  - WHEATON TRIANGLE, COMPETITION Silver Springs Maryland (undated) (not built) [Commercial], large urban apartment project
    - Project material, oversize (Box 94A)
    - Slides, site plans, elevations, models; 10 (Box S-5)
  - WICKWIRE RESIDENCE ADDITION (WIC), Cortland, New York (not built) [Residential]
    Small residential addition. Sponsor/client: Charles Wickwire. Collaborators/partners: Associated Architect: Lee Hodgden
    - Drawings, 1963-1964; working drawings (Tube 156)
  - WILLARD STATE HOSPITAL - GENERAL* 7116 County Route 132 Willard, New York [Health]
    (Alternate names: Willard Drug Treatment Campus)
    New administrative office building and rehabilitation center for large New York state psychiatric hospital. Sponsor/client: NYS Health and Mental Hygiene Facilities Improvement Corporation.
    - Project material, 1968-1982; specifications, site analysis, clipping, architectural description, article, text from exhibition board, awards submission (Box 64A)
    - Project material, oversize (Box 94C)
  - WILLARD STATE HOSPITAL ADMINISTRATION BUILDING (WAB) 7116 County Route 132 Willard, New York (1971) [Health]
    New administrative office building for large New York state psychiatric hospital. Sponsor/client: NYS Health and Mental Hygiene Facilities Improvement Corporation. Collaborators/partners: Assoc. Architects: Frederic P. Wiedersum Associates; Structural: Severud Associates (NYC), Dr. Donald P. Greenberg; Mechanical: Galson & Galson, Flack & Kurtz (NYC); Contractor: V. Giordano Constr.; Photog.: C. Hadley Smith, LYONFOTO, William H. Allen.
    - Drawings, 1948-1970; preliminary detail and design studies (Tube 157)
    - Drawings, undated; site studies, working drawings (Tube 158)
    - Drawings, 1969; working drawings (Tube 159)
    - Drawings, 1969; final drawings (Tube 160)
    - Drawings, 1969; working drawings (Tube 161)
    - Drawings, 1969; working drawings (Tube 162)
    - Drawings, 1969-1970; working drawings (blueprints), contract documents (Tube 163)
    - Drawings, 1968; early presentation drawings (Tube 164)
    - Presentation board 60, site plan, "Department of Hygiene - Health and Mental Hygiene Facilities Equipment Corporation - Werner Seligmann, Architect - Galson & Galson, Engineers"
    - Presentation board 61, elevation
    - Presentation board 62, elevation
    - Presentation board 63, plan
    - Presentation board 64, first floor plan
    - Presentation board 65, elevation
    - Presentation board 66, second floor plan
    - Presentation board 67, elevation
    - Presentation board 68, photos of model
    - Presentation board 69, section, photo of model
    - Presentation board 70, section, photo of model
    - Presentation board 71, basement plan
    - Presentation board 72, working details, superimposed symmetries
    - Presentation board 73, photos of exterior and interior
    - Presentation board 74, plans, elevations, sections
    - Presentation board 75, elevations, sections
    - Presentation board 76, working details, superimposed symmetries (color)
    - Project material, 1971-1973; exterior and interior details (Box 61)
    - Project material, 1971; exterior and interior details (Box 62)
    - Project material, 1969; site plans, plans, model, sections, elevations, working drawings; sketches (Box 63)
    - Project material, oversize (Box 94C)
    - Slides, title slide (dated 1970), site plans, elevations, sections, plans, analytical and explanatory diagrams, working details, models, earlier existing structures, referential images, facade, side and back views, interiors, interior details; 360 (Box S-5)
  - WILLARD STATE HOSPITAL REHABILITATION CENTER (WRC) 7116 County Route 132 Willard, New York (not built) [Health]
    Proposal for rehabilitation facility for large New York state psychiatric hospital. Sponsor/client: NYS Health and Mental Hygiene Facilities Improvement Corporation. Collaborators/partners: Associated Architects: Frederic P. Wiedersum & Associates; Mechanical: Flack & Kurtz (NYC); Structural: Severud Associates (NYC); Photography: C. Hadley Smith (Ithaca).
    - Drawings, undated; design development drawings (Tube 165)
    - Drawings, 1968; design development drawings (Tube 166)
    - Drawings, undated; design development drawings, Mylar photos of model (Tube 167)
    - Drawings, 1969-1970; site development and landscape drawings (Tube 168)
    - Drawings, 1969; room layouts (Tube 169)